Akira Takezawa

Address: Indiranagar, Bengaluru, India - 560038 Contact: (+91) 9513313099 | akiratakezawa71@gmail.com Personal website: https://samurainote.github.io/ & Linkedin

DATA SCIENCE ASSOCIATES

Profound, Insightful and result driven Data Science Associates with sharp analytics skills and experience in E-commerce and Matching platform business domein. Highly motivated self-taught Machine Learning Engineer, with over 20 personal implementations of developping ML/DL model. Present area of research/development is Natural Language Processing. Also almni of Machine Learning bootcamp 2018 winter batch from Byte Academy in NY. Excells in Data Diagnosis from Business Contexts. Outstands in define the problem which should be focused, collaborate as a Team in English and Japanese.

AREA OF EXPERTISE:

Machine Learning | Natural Language Processing | Image Processing | Time-series Data Analytics | Relational Database | Business Analytics | Data Mining | Marketing KPI Management | Data Visualization | Data Presentation | Statistics |

PROJECTS / PUBLICATION _____

- Seq2Seq Automatic Encoder-Decoder for English Chatbot: https://bit.ly/2U5hEqk
- Collaborative Filtering with SVD for Book Recommender System: https://bit.ly/2UMtylN
- HR meets Machine Learning, "Who will Leave your Company in This Year?": https://bit.ly/2W52HBU
- Speech Recognition and Classification by using Convolutional Neural Network: https://bit.ly/2OkdJQU
- How Dimension of Data Changes in each Seq2Seq Neural Network Layer: https://bit.ly/2Hw8pth

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES _____

- Platforms: MacOS Mojave version 10.14.3
- Language: Core Python, R, HTML5, CSS3
- Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Chainer, Scikit-learn, Genism, NLTK, Scipy, Numpy, Seaborn
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow / ML Bootcamp from NY Byte Academy in Bangalore, India, Descember 2018 - March 2019 I joined one of the most creditable Data Science Bootcamp from New York, which provides real industry-driven capstone courses for 3 months. We basically learn theory of Machine Learning in the morning, and in afternoon we implement several machine learning algorithm for real business problem, and finally conducted personal projects. The participants with diverse background, like from Software Engineer to Business Analyst, collaborates on the same Data Science Projects. The whole hands-on intensive course are led by industry experienced professinal who also has master degree from IIM.

What I learned:

- Object Oriented Programming and Advanced Python
- Data Structures and Algorithm
- Relational Database Management: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Web scraping by selenium and beautifulsoup
- Machine Learning for Regression and Classification, Clustering Task
- Recommendation System by using Collaborative Filtering
- Deep Learning for Image and Text Data

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - Akira Takezawa

Bussiness Analyst / Xvolve Inc. in Tokyo, Japan, July 2018 - November 2018

Manages all marketing strategy and metrics of the dating web service for upper-class Man and Woman called "Bachelor" in Japan. Try to get voiceless Insights from quantitative Data, and designed full User Experience from the customer acquisition to the paid user, and finally to the continuity. In addition, I defined suitable KPI for particular terms by giving careful research of other worldwide subscription business, operated web advertisement by data driven analysis, improved core matching algorithm.

Key Achievements:

- Improved Paid Conversion Rate by 10% through correlation analysis between paid user and demographical data or UX.
- Acomplished lowest CPA (custemer acquision cost) by analytical improvement of web advirtisment.
- Built A KPI Tracking Dashboard on google spreadsheet for team members which is automatically updated once per a week.

Data Analyst / Cospa Creation Co. in Tokyo, Japan, April 2017 - June 2018

The company, which operates one of the largest online drop shipping platform in Japan which is called "通販素材.com,". I conducted Data Mining on over 2000 our private products, mostly centering on interiors. Mixed both quantitative actual Sales Data Analysis and making hypotheses based on qualitative research on market trends or needs for product planning team. Exciting part of job was break down physical products into Variables like function or some SEO keyword which is also important element for sales result.

Key Achievements:

- Become A Sales Top Data Analysts at the first year among other analysts who joined the company in the same year.
- Built Hand-made Data Visualization Dashboard on microsoft excel for other Data Analysts to improve team productivity.
- Introduced SEO based product sales result Analysis to the team which wasn't used to have.

Official Certification

- IBM Data Science Bootcamp Certification from Jigsaw Academy in Balgalore, India
- Machine Learning / Deep Learning Bootcamp Almuni from Byte Academy in New York, US
- Official Writer of Towards Data Science on Medium: https://bit.ly/2uE3m1A
- Toefl ibt 86

Academic Background _____

- Graduated from Machine Learning winter bootcamp of 2018 from Byte Academy in NY
- Economics Bachelor Degree of Economics, Hokkaido University: one of the top 5 uni in Japan
- Moka High School: entranced and graduated as the Top student.

Data Science Portfolio

- Machine Learning Personal Projects on GitHub: https://github.com/samurainote/portfolio
- Data Science Articles on Medium: https://medium.com/shortcutnlp

職務経歴書

2019年3月12日 竹澤 輝

個人サイト: https://samurainote.github.io/

連絡先: (+91) 9513313099 | akiratakezawa71@gmail.com

【参考リンク】

- ・機械学習/ディープラーニングを用いた個人実装記録: https://github.com/samurainote/portfolio
- ・機械学習/自然言語処理に関する英文記事投稿: https://medium.com/shortcutnlp

[Data Science Projects/Publication]

- · Seq2Seq Automatic Encoder-Decoder for English Chatbot: https://bit.ly/2U5hEqk
- · Collaborative Filtering with SVD for Book Recommender System: https://bit.ly/2UMtylN
- · HR meets Machine Learning, "Who will Leave your Company in This Year?": https://bit.ly/2W52HBU
- · Speech Recognition and Classification by using Convolutional Neural Network: https://bit.ly/2OkdJQU
- · How Dimension of Data Changes in each Seq2Seq Neural Network Layer: https://bit.ly/2Hw8pth

【技術スキル】

- · 開発環境: MacOS Mojave 10.14.3
- ・プログラミング言語: Python(core), R, HTML5, CSS3
- ・ライブラリ: Tensorflow, Kras, scikit-learn, Scipy, Chainer, Genism, NLTK, Numpy, Seaborn
- ・データベース言語: MySQL, PostgreSQL

【職務要約】

北海道大学経済学部を卒業後、インテリアのEコマースベンチャーにて商品企画室に所属し、年3カ月の間データアナリストを担当。その後、創業期のスタートアップにマーケティング責任者として参画。消費財/サービスと異なる2種類のビジネスドメインにおいて、データマイニング&アナリティクスを経験。2018年12月より、機械学習技術による非構造化データのビジネス活用に大きな可能性を感じ、データサイエンス&機械学習の技術習得を開始。ニューヨークのByte Academy が主催する Machine Learning Bootcamp に参加する傍ら、自然言語処理を中心とした20弱の個人実装を経て現在に至る。

【職務経歴】*逆編年体

職業訓練: Data Science Fellow of Byte Academy / 2019 Winter Bootcamp (https://byteacademy.co/hiring/)

期間:2019/01-2019/04

概要:

データサイエンス領域への就職をゴールとした強化プログラムに参加。3ヶ月の間、機械学習を中心に 午前は理論、午後は実装を平日毎日行う。言語は主に Pythonを使用。以下のトピックを学習。

- · Object Oriented Programming and Advanced Python
- · Data Structures and Algorithm
- · Relational Database Management
- · Web scraping by selenium and beautifulsoup
- · Machine Learning for Regression and Classification, Clustering Task
- · Deep Learning for Image and Text Data

*職務経歴つづき

職種:Bussiness Analyst / マーケティング部門責任者

期間:2018/08-2018/11

所属:株式会社 Xvolve *中途入社

ドメイン:デーティングアプリケーション/オンラインサービス

概要:

アッパー層向けのデーティングサービス「Bachelor」の全マーケティング業務を管理。ユーザーの獲得から有料化、継続までを一気通貫してデザインする。サブスクリプションビジネスにおける KPI の設計から中期での目標管理を遂行。その他ウェブ広告運用、マッチングアルゴリズムの改善まで幅広く着手。

成果:

プロダクトを通してどの顧客データを握るべきかという視点でサービスの設計に携わる。また集めたデータを活用し分析だけでなく、分析結果を収益に反映させることにこだわり、下記を達成。

- ・既存の課金ユーザーと顧客データ&ログ解析を用いて、有料化コンバージョン率を10%改善
- ・ウェブ広告の運用において定量的な分析&改善により、前任者を上回る最低 CPA&CTR を達成
- ・チームメンバー全員が常に、週次の各 KPI 達成状況を把握できるダッシュボードを構築

職種: Data Analyst / プロダクト開発部門

期間:2017/04-2018/07

所属:株式会社 Cospa Creation *新卒入社

ドメイン:インテリア&ファッション / E コマース

概要:

国内最大級のドロップシッピングプラットフォーム「通販素材.com」を運営する同社にて、インテリアを中心とした累計 2,000 超の自社商品のデータマイニングを実施。市場トレンドやニーズに対する定性的なリサーチと、定量的な実際の販売データ分析から仮説を立てて商品企画を実施。

成果:

同時期に同じ部署に配属された新卒&中途社員 1 2名のうち、1年目に分析を担当した商品で売上トップを記録。データを分析するにあたり、成果を出すために下記を行う。

- ・未整理のデータを粘り強く仕分け、愚直に可視化することでインプットの量で差をつけること
- ・商品をウェブと消費財独自の変数にブレークダウンすることで、定量的な分析を可能にした
- ・SEO に関するナレッジが不足していた分析チームに、SEO の視点での売上分析やツールを導入

【学歴】

- · 2018 Winter Machine Learing Bootcamp by Byte Academy in New York, US (2019/01 2019/04 卒業)
- ・北海道大学経済学部経済学科:統計言語 R を活用した計量経済学&留学生特別クラスの単位取得
- · 栃木県立真岡高校: 首席入学、首席卒業

【資格】

- · IBM Data Science certification in Bangalore, India (2019/01 2018/04 取得)
- · Basic and Advanced Python from Mytectra in Bangalore, India (2018/11 2019/01 参加)
- · TOEFL ibt score: 86 (2016/12 取得)

【自己PR】

これまでのキャリアで意識して育ててきたスキルは下記3つ。

- ・ビジネスアナリティクス能力:市場ドメインやビジネスモデルに対する読解力を生かして、データ分析の結果を粘り強く PL に反映させた成功体験がある。
- ・リサーチスキル:常に0から学習しようとせず、他社(他者)の先行事例や失敗を徹底的に調べる。 問題解決の勘所を最短で捉えるために必要な、リサーチ能力がある。
- ・英語による情報収集力:機械学習領域の専門知識と英語力を掛け合わせ、最先端かつ最良なソースや 論文にアクセスすることができるため、効率的に質の高いインプットを継続できる。

機械学習やデータサイエンスなどテクニカルな知識や実装能力を活かし、データサイエンティストとして 各企業が持つデータという経営資源をどう活用し、事業にレバレッジをかけてスケールさせていけるのか という部分をこれからのキャリアを通して、突き詰めていきたいです。